SUMMARY

I'm specialized in computer vision, reasoning, planning, real-time systems and automation. I have more than 5 years of experience in computer vision heavy projects and industries as biotech, retail or ADAS. I have experience in startups, scale-ups and big consulting firms. I focus on task automation to minimize human time spent on repetitive tasks, enabling them to concentrate on delivering value.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ LUMICKS

Amsterdam (Netherlands) | Jul 2021 - Currently

- Development of data acquisition system for new generation microscope. Using C++17/20.
- Development of **onnxruntime** based imaging inference libraries.
- Maintenance, upgrade and creation of conan recipes for build system.



• Prototyping of real-time imaging acquisition systems for high force environments. Using **FFmpeg**, **OpenCV**, **mbedOS**, **C++**, **Python and electronics design**.



Remote (Netherlands) | Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

 Incorporation of Emotion Research Lab computer vision technology to Uniphore's during acquisition phase.



LUMXCKS

Deployment of a **highly scalable Deep learning platform** for video processing in **real-time**.

AI LEAD @ Emotion Research Lab

Valencia (Spain), Remote (Netherlands) | Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

- Responsible of AI technology and development.
- Develop several products up to the acquisition of the company from a 100M\$ Series C company.
- Deployment of a highly scalable Deep learning platform for video processing in the cloud using AWS ECS.
- Emotion recognition pipeline implementation in C++ and Tensorflow.
- Development of a **multi-platform** automatic release for Windows, Linux (CPU, GPU) and **Jetson** platform.
- Core library migration from C++98 to C++14.

COMPUTER VISION DEVELOPER @ CISCO/Pi School

Rome (Italy) | Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- Research of solutions for the task of real time depth estimation from monocular images. GANs and VAEs were the developed proofs of concepts.
- Development done inside a collaboration program between PI School and Cisco.



COMPUTER VISION DEVELOPER @ XESOL Innovation

Vigo (Spain) | Ago 2017 - Oct 2018

- Development and fine-tuning of object detection pipelines for embedded devices deployment based on Deep Learning (**Caffe** and **Tensorflow**).
- R&D of pipelines focusing in fast inference (Intel Movidius, TensorRT).
- Development of a system for vehicles and pedestrian counting and tracking in real-time. (Jetson Board, C++14)
- Development of a semi-automated development and testing suite for deep **XESOL**innovation learning models to decrease the time between experiments.



JUNIOR CONSULTANT @ Capgemini

Valencia (Spain) | Feb 2016 - Feb 2017

Full stack web development.

Keywords: Java, Spring, Hibernate, ExtJS and Oracle RDBMS.



DEVELOPER @ **Chivesoft**(self-employed)

Valencia (Spain) | Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

- Android development: Facebook friends quiz, sickness predictor, several speed reflex games.
- Development of booking platform for sport centers.
 Keywords: Android, JavaScript, Java.
- Embedded device prototyping and development.
 Keywords: C, C++, CORTEX-M4, ANDROID, 3D Printing, Java.

DEVELOPER @ **Chivesoft**(self-employed)

Valencia (Spain) | Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

- Sales team support from the technical point of view.
- Technical presentations to potential customers.



EDUCATION

Oct 2021 – Jul 2023 MSC ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE'S RESEARCH - Specialty in reasoning and planning. Universidad Internacional Menéndez Pelayo (Spain)

Master's thesis: Satellite imaging analysis for invasive algae detection in the surface of lakes.

Feb 2017 - Mar 2018 SELF-DRIVING CAR NANODEGREE

The program contains the next topics: **Computer vision**, **deep learning**, **machine learning**, **sensor fusion**, **localization**, **control systems** and **path planning**.

It is focused on developing the necessary understanding and technical skills to create an autonomous vehicle able to drive safely in public roads.

2010-2014 DEGREE IN INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING -

Specialty in embedded system and Real-Time computing. Universitat Politècnica de València. (Spain) Final thesis (A grade): Cross-platform Qt application for the automatic control of liquids tank. QML, C++

2014 SPRING SEMESTER ERASMUS SCHOLARSHIP

Faculty of Electrical Engineering. České vysoké učení technické v Praze. Prague (Czech Republic)

OTHER SIDE PROJECTS

- Telegram bot to detect and classify fish species from photos. Telegram API, Python, Tensorflow.
- Autonomous maritime drone. Raspberry Pi, C++, Python, Qt, QML, 3D modeling & printing.
- Vehicle detection & tracking with OpenCV and deep learning approaches. Python, OpenCV, Keras,
 Machine learning.
- Lane detection in the road using computer vision techniques. Python, OpenCV.
- Traffic sign identification and classification. Python, Tensorflow, OpenCV.

